<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
<title type="text">Twitch Tips</title>
<generator uri="https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll">Jekyll</generator>
<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://twitchtips.com/feed.xml" />
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://twitchtips.com" />
<updated>2016-10-08T19:10:12+01:00</updated>
<id>https://twitchtips.com/</id>
<author>
  <name>Twitch Tips</name>
  <uri>https://twitchtips.com/</uri>
  <email>contact@twitchtips.com</email>
</author>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using KapChat]]></title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://twitchtips.com/using-kapchat/" />
    <id>https://twitchtips.com/using-kapchat</id>
    <published>2015-10-18T00:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2015-10-18T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Twitch Tips</name>
      <uri>https://twitchtips.com</uri>
      <email>contact@twitchtips.com</email>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-kapchat&quot;&gt;What is KapChat?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://nightdev.com/kapchat/&quot;&gt;KapChat&lt;/a&gt; is a hosted service that can be used to add Twitch chat to your stream. Designed to reflect Twitch chat, it features chat badges, username colors, emotes and real-time removing of messages. With 8 built-in themes, KapChat has a design theme that will fit your stream. You can even customize fine details using the Full CSS Support. KapChat also displays all of your favorite FrankerFaceZ and BetterTTV emotes so you can never miss a SourPls in your chat. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;features&quot;&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;twitch-protocols&quot;&gt;Twitch Protocols&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chat Tags&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Deleted Messages&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Emotes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Subscriptions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Usercolors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;customization&quot;&gt;Customization&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Themes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Full CSS support (for advanced users) &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chat Fade&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Show/Hide Bots&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;third-party-emote-support&quot;&gt;Third Party Emote Support&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;BetterTTV Emotes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;FrankerFaceZ Emotes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;adding-to-stream&quot;&gt;Adding to Stream&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adding KapChat couldn’t be easier with common streaming software. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;obs&quot;&gt;OBS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Head over to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://nightdev.com/kapchat/&quot;&gt;KapChat&lt;/a&gt; page and click the green install button.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Kapchat uses a CLR Browser plugin which has been added with a batch file to make the install easier. After downloading, unzipping the file, install the plugin by double clicking the install.bat file. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;After installing the OBS browser plugin you now get to create your chat display. Clicking next on the KapChat Installation will bring you to a page with all sorts of customization. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Username: This is the channel in which the chat will be taken from. &lt;strong&gt;Use the channel name and not the Twitch link.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chat Fade: The checkbox enables or disables the chat fade option which will fade out messages over a select amount of time. This feature is very useful if you don’t want chat lines stuck there until someone sends a message.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chat Fade Length: In seconds the default time is 30 seconds, feel free to play around with these time settings. If the Chat Fade checkbox is unchecked you can ignore this setting.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Show Bots: By default KapChat ignores bots. Custom bots can be added in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://manage.betterttv.net/channel&quot;&gt;BTTV Manager Page&lt;/a&gt;, common bots (e.g. nightbot, moobot, xanbot) will already be recognized and do not need to be added. &lt;strong&gt;Checking this will show all bot messages.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chat Theme: Select a chat theme from the list of 8. You can preview the display by clicking the “preview” button.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;When all the settings are to your liking you can continue. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A hosted URL will be generated and this will be copied to OBS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;To display:&lt;br /&gt;
Add a new source for obs and select “CLR Browser”, give it a name of your choosing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;URL: Paste the Hosted URL generated by the KapChat page into the URL textbox. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dimensions:  If you’re unsure of a size NightDev suggests a &lt;code&gt;height of 600&lt;/code&gt; and a &lt;code&gt;width of 300&lt;/code&gt;. You can then edit these to your liking and placement in your overlay.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You now have a chat overlay in your stream! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you ever need to customize any of the main features (e.g Chat Fade, Theme) head back to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://nightdev.com/kapchat/&quot;&gt;KapChat&lt;/a&gt; site and get a new Hosted URL and replace the old URL in your source.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;obs-multiplatform&quot;&gt;OBS MultiPlatform&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OBS MultiPlatform Brower Plugin can be found &lt;a href=&quot;https://obsproject.com/forum/resources/browser-plugin.115/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and contains an install guide. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;xsplit&quot;&gt;XSplit&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;XSplit has a built in web plugin so there is no need to download anything. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Complete the same steps in the OBS guide skipping everything OBS related, and get the Hosted Link. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In XSplit navagate to Add -&amp;gt; Other -&amp;gt; Webpage URL. And paste the generated URL into the popout box. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;From there you can edit the size and placement within xsplit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;custom-css-advanced&quot;&gt;Custom CSS (Advanced)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the default themes don’t have something your looking for you can change them using Custom CSS. &lt;strong&gt;Custom CSS is for advanced users and Nightdev will not offer support for CSS related issues.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Nightdev has provided CSS selectors for people to improve upon on. They can be found on the 4th page of the install directions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;To access on OBS, click on the CSS tab at the top of the CLR Browser settings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;To access on XSplit, right-click the webpage source -&amp;gt; Enable Custom CSS Checkbox on HTML section -&amp;gt; Edit CSS. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For useful CSS and KapChat tips, check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://community.nightdev.com/c/kapchat&quot;&gt;NightDev Fourms&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://nightdev.com/kapchat/&quot;&gt;KapChat&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://community.nightdev.com&quot;&gt;NightDev Fourms&lt;/a&gt; is owned and operated by NightDev, LLC.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.xsplit.com&quot;&gt;XSplit&lt;/a&gt; is owned by  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.splitmedialabs.com/&quot;&gt;SplitmediaLabs, Ltd.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://obsproject.com/&quot;&gt;OBS&lt;/a&gt; is an open source software maintained on their &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jp9000/OBS&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitchtips.com/using-kapchat/&quot;&gt;Using KapChat&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Twitch Tips at &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitchtips.com&quot;&gt;Twitch Tips&lt;/a&gt; on October 18, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>


  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Animated Social Media Popup]]></title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://twitchtips.com/social-media-popup/" />
    <id>https://twitchtips.com/social-media-popup</id>
    <published>2015-09-06T00:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2015-09-06T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Twitch Tips</name>
      <uri>https://twitchtips.com</uri>
      <email>contact@twitchtips.com</email>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ever wanted to let your audience know you’re also on social media without repeating yourself? This quick guide goes through setting up an animated social media popup!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;853&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/VHZ7MjrQpL4&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This video was brought to you by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitch.tv/nerdordie&quot;&gt;NerdOrDie&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You can also find NerdOrDie on:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/NerdsPwn&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/NerdorDie&quot;&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitchtips.com/social-media-popup/&quot;&gt;Animated Social Media Popup&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Twitch Tips at &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitchtips.com&quot;&gt;Twitch Tips&lt;/a&gt; on September 06, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>


  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Noticing Harmful Users]]></title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://twitchtips.com/harmful-users/" />
    <id>https://twitchtips.com/harmful-users</id>
    <published>2015-07-20T00:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2015-07-20T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Twitch Tips</name>
      <uri>https://twitchtips.com</uri>
      <email>contact@twitchtips.com</email>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, you may have spotted several accounts, such as ‘TwitchSupport_[Name]’, going around saying they are Twitch Staff and telling people to do everything that is going to get their account closed down. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-to-look-out-for&quot;&gt;What to look out for&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are the usual things trolls and scammers use to convince people to listen to them. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;no-sound&quot;&gt;No Sound&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Often, this is used at the start of the troll and is said to be a consequence of a virus. Sometimes, the fact that there is no sound can be true. Make sure that there is sound on your stream before taking action.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;system-32&quot;&gt;System 32&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is usually telling people that System 32 is a virus and that you should delete it immediately. Trolls also spam ‘message deleted by system32’. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you did not know, System 32 is the folder that keeps your Windows OS installation. If you delete this folder, you have practically deleted your computer. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Never edit stuff in this type of folder unless you are sure of what you are doing. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;destruction&quot;&gt;Destruction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before you saw trolls raiding channels, you would hope that someone who was told to pour milk in their console’s fan vents would have thought this was a bad idea. Sadly, that isn’t true. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;No matter who tells you it does, pouring rice into your hard drive does not stop a static sound. Please, make sure you know what you are doing before doing things to the inside of machines and ignore what they are saying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;stream-key&quot;&gt;Stream Key&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here we have the most common attack. Usually, someone will add you on Skype and ask for your stream key. Don’t give it to them. Otherwise, you may find something you don’t want being streamed to your channel. Instead, block them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;usernames&quot;&gt;Usernames&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users often have offensive usernames and comments when they are trolling, usually racist ones. If you see a large number of offensive users gathering, be ready for what has been explained here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;skype-details&quot;&gt;Skype Details&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lot’s of people have Skype. But most don’t know how dangerous it can be. If someone is able to get your Skype Name, it is very easy for them to get your IP. This can then result in DDoS attacks (lots of traffic being sent to your IP that may result in your stream doing offline). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For protection, make sure to set up a proxy following &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitchtips.com/protecting-yourself/&quot;&gt;this existing guide.&lt;/a&gt; You may also get random friend requests from people who claim they are Support Staff. Twitch never offers assistance over Skype and you should therefore not comply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;staff-or-admin-impersonation&quot;&gt;Staff or Admin Impersonation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main way trolls get people to listen is through pretending to be Staff. The only way a user can be considered Official is if they have &lt;a href=&quot;http://imgur.com/HLFg5Fa&quot;&gt;one of these badges&lt;/a&gt; to represent what they do. You can also use the existing &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitchtips.com/user-checker/&quot;&gt;user checker&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If their type is “user”, they are not official. Some people often mistake @TwitchSupport Volunteers and other users for an official representative of Twitch, they are not. In addition, do not give impersonators moderator powers. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Some streamers do this and then anyone that tried to stop the streamer pouring cereal in a disc tray would be banned instantly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you find &lt;a href=&quot;http://imgur.com/RB9chxb&quot;&gt;something like this,&lt;/a&gt; you pretty much have the full package. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-to-do&quot;&gt;What to do&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;account-is-compromised&quot;&gt;Account is Compromised&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Email support@twitch.tv with as much information as possible to prove you own the account. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wait for your account to be closed. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://help.twitch.tv/customer/portal/emails/new&quot;&gt;Open a ticket&lt;/a&gt; to get your account back. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;information-leaked&quot;&gt;Information Leaked&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reset everything immediately, most importantly passwords and stream keys. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;users-trolling-scamming-or-using-racist-usernames&quot;&gt;Users trolling, scamming or using racist usernames.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ban them from your channel. Using /subscribers can be a good way to stop chat while the issue blows over. Also, make sure to &lt;a href=&quot;http://help.twitch.tv/customer/portal/articles/725568-how-to-file-a-report&quot;&gt;report them.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stay safe!&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;Post written and contributed by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Heep123&quot;&gt;@Heep123&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitchtips.com/harmful-users/&quot;&gt;Noticing Harmful Users&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Twitch Tips at &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitchtips.com&quot;&gt;Twitch Tips&lt;/a&gt; on July 20, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>


  

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to setup the Elgato Game Capture HD in OBS]]></title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://twitchtips.com/elgato-game-capture-hd-obs/" />
    <id>https://twitchtips.com/elgato-game-capture-hd-obs</id>
    <published>2014-06-28T00:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2014-06-28T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Twitch Tips</name>
      <uri>https://twitchtips.com</uri>
      <email>contact@twitchtips.com</email>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Welcome to this guide which will show you how to setup your &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gamecapture.com&quot;&gt;Elgato Game Capture HD&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.obsproject.com&quot;&gt;OBS&lt;/a&gt;. Before we continue, please make sure you have each of these: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gamecapture.com&quot;&gt;Elgato Game Capture HD&lt;/a&gt; plugged in and setup with your console&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gamecapture.com&quot;&gt;Game Capture HD software/drivers&lt;/a&gt; installed.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.obsproject.com&quot;&gt;OBS&lt;/a&gt; 32 bit installed. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-1-open-obs-32bit-and-go-to-the-settings&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 1: Open OBS 32Bit, and go to the settings.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;a href=&quot;/images/elgato_hd/1.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/elgato_hd/1.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-2-general&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 2: General&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make a new profile. For the purpose of this tutorial, we’ll call it “Game Capture HD”, then click “add”  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;a href=&quot;/images/elgato_hd/2.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/elgato_hd/2.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-3-encoding&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 3: Encoding&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leave the encoder on “X264”. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leave both CBR and VBR checked. These are Twitch requirements.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Run a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.speedtest.net&quot;&gt;speedtest&lt;/a&gt; to find out your approximate upload speed. Now you have some options. Depending on your upload speed, you can do a few things. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If 75% of your upload speed equates to 3400kbps, (which is the maximum Twitch will take), then you can set your upload speed to that. Be warned however that many people cannot watch a stream with that high bit rate. For new streamers, a good balance between quality and watchability is 2000kbps. You will also need to take into consideration your own internet upload speed. If your maximum is 2mbps(2000kbps) then you may want to set your upload to 1500kbps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For audio encoding, select AAC, set the format to 48kHz and select a bit rate. Remember, audio bit rate will &lt;strong&gt;ADD to the total bit rate&lt;/strong&gt; being streamed to Twitch and your viewers. A good balance between quality and bit rate is 96. As for Mono or Stereo, the option is up to you, but we recommend stereo.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;a href=&quot;/images/elgato_hd/3.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/elgato_hd/3.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-4-broadcast-settings&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 4: Broadcast settings&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For mode, choose “Live stream”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Streaming service is of course Twitch/Justin.tv(don’t worry, you will only stream to Twitch)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Server should be the closest one to you. If you are not sure, we recommend you use &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.teamliquid.net/forum/tech-support/326034-jtvping-find-your-best-twitchtv-server&quot;&gt;JTVPing&lt;/a&gt; to find the closest one to you. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your Pathkey/Stream key can be found by going to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitch.tv&quot;&gt;Twitch&lt;/a&gt; then your dashboard, and then the “Stream key” tab. Hit “show”, and copy and paste the full stream key, including any letters, into OBS. &lt;strong&gt;(Note&lt;/strong&gt;: Never show your stream key publicly or give it to anyone you don’t trust.&lt;strong&gt;)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Keep “Auto reconnect” checked. This is useful when there is a sudden disconnect or network error, OBS will automatically try to start up the stream again. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You should not need to touch “Minimize network impact”. If you do have network issues, ask on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://obsproject.com/forum/list/questions-and-help.5/&quot;&gt;OBS forums&lt;/a&gt; first. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Save to file is a very useful option. What this does is it will save an EXACT copy of your stream to a folder of your choosing. This can be useful for cutting out stream highlights for YouTube later. If you decide to use this feature, the naming of the files is a little weird. If you name the file &lt;strong&gt;%&lt;/strong&gt;, then the name of the saved file will be date_time.mp4. If you name the file ““Stream recording”, the first time you stream, it will be “Stream recording”, and the next time it will be “Stream recording1”. Hopefully in &lt;a href=&quot;https://obsproject.com/forum/threads/obs-redux.7736/&quot;&gt;OBS Studio (OBS 2.0)&lt;/a&gt; there will be a more graceful solution. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hotkeys, who doesn’t like hotkeys. If you choose to use hotkeys, make sure they are not close to any keys you use often. You don’t want to accidentally start and/or stop your stream. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ignore any warnings OBS is giving you, we will fix them.   &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;a href=&quot;/images/elgato_hd/4.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/elgato_hd/4.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-5-video&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 5: Video&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do not touch “Video Adapter”. This will be set to your graphics card.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Base resolution should be set to “Custom” and 1080p. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To get a nice looking stream, and reduce OBS’s CPU usage, downscaling the stream by 1.50x to 1280x720p is recommended. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Set the filter to “Lanczos”. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Set the FPS to 30, this is a limitation from the Game Capture HD. If the Game Capture HD receives 1080p video from the console, the maximum recording/streaming FPS is 30. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;a href=&quot;/images/elgato_hd/5.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/elgato_hd/5.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-6-audio&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 6: Audio&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Desktop audio device will be whatever your computer audio is playing through. In most cases, this will be your headphones. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Microphone is pretty self explanatory. Keep it on default to use your default computer mic for OBS. If you have a headset mic and a USB mic like a Blue Yeti connected, you may need to manually select the Blue Yeti. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Show only connected devices” should be checked. This makes sure you don’t select anything that isn’t actually there, which can cause problems. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you want to use Push-to-talk, that is up to you. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We now need to change “Mic time offset”. There is about a 1.4-1.5 second delay from what happens on your TV/Monitor to when the Game Capture HD shows it on your computer. For this reason, we need to delay the mic by the same amount of time so that the video and audio is synced. A good offset time to start at is 1500ms. You might need to change this to 1450ms or 1550ms or even higher or lower depending on your experience. There is currently a bug in OBS where the delay from the Game Capture HD increases over time. This may not be resolved in this version of OBS. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;a href=&quot;/images/elgato_hd/6.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/elgato_hd/6.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-7-advanced&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 7: Advanced&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Multithreaded optimizations: Keep this checked&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Process priority class: Do not change unless issues arise, in which case you should ask on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://obsproject.com/forum/&quot;&gt;OBS forums&lt;/a&gt; first. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leave all other settings in the &lt;strong&gt;General&lt;/strong&gt; box as they are&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;X264 preset: Next to bit rate and resolution, changing this settings can effect the quality of your stream a lot, as well as much CPU OBS uses. The slower the preset, the better the video quality, but the more CPU OBS will use. This list can help you determine which preset you can use:  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intel:&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dual core Intel i3 23XX or higher: ultrafast/superfast&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Quad core Intel i5 25XX or higher: Veryfast/Faster&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;8-core Intel i7 26XX or higher: Fast/Medium&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;12-core Intel i7 3930k or higher: slow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AMD:&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Due to the low speed/IPC(Instructions per clock) of AMD CPU’s, it is generally not recommended to stream with a dual core or lower.&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;AMD FX series: &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;AMD FX 4100 or higher: Ultrafast/Veryfast&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;AMD FX 6100 or higher: Veryfast/Faster&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;AMD FX 8320 or higher: Fast/Medium&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE:&lt;/strong&gt; Any X264 preset beyond slow will provide for very little image quality gain and exponential CPU usage increase. We do not recommend going above Medium unless you have a monster CPU or extreme over clock.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Encoding profile: Set this to main. If you set it to high there will be a marginal video quality increase, but some phones/tablets may not be able to view your stream. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Keyframe: Set to 2. This is a Twitch requirement.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use CFR: Keep this checked.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do &lt;strong&gt;NOT&lt;/strong&gt; touch any of the other settings unless you have extensive knowledge of X264, OBS and video encoding, or if you are having issues and have been instructed so on the OBS forums.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-8-noise-gate&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 8: Noise gate&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This is something you can play around with on your own, but simply, it will mute your microphone when you are not talking. This may be useful for people with a lot of background noise. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-9-adding-a-scene&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 9: Adding a scene&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Now that you have configured your settings, we can start setting up the Elgato Game Capture HD in OBS. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In the left hand box at the bottom, right click to “Add scene”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;a href=&quot;/images/elgato_hd/7.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/elgato_hd/7.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-10-name-your-scene&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 10: Name your scene&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For the purpose of this tutorial, we will name the scene “Elgato Game Capture HD”. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;a href=&quot;/images/elgato_hd/8.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/elgato_hd/8.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-11-global-sources&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 11: Global Sources&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Now lets add your Game Capture HD as a source. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click on “Global Sources”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;a href=&quot;/images/elgato_hd/9.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/elgato_hd/9.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-12-add-a-video-device&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 12: Add a video device&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click on “Add” &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click on “Video capture device”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;a href=&quot;/images/elgato_hd/10.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/elgato_hd/10.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-13-name-the-video-capture-device&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 13: Name the Video capture device&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For easy remembering, name the source “Elgato Game Capture HD”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;a href=&quot;/images/elgato_hd/11.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/elgato_hd/11.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-14-select-the-device&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 14: Select the device&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;By default, the Game Capture HD should be selected. If not, go to the drop down menu at the top, and select the Elgato Game Capture HD. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Under Audio, in the drop down menu, choose “Use device audio”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Under Audio, set the device to “Output to stream only”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Under video, check the box that says “Use buffering” and set the time to 0. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Now click ok, and the window should close. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;a href=&quot;/images/elgato_hd/12.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/elgato_hd/12.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-15-add-the-game-capture-hd-in-the-scene&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 15: Add the Game Capture HD in the scene&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Right click in the box to the right of the scenes box. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click “Add”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A menu will come up. Go to “Global sources”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;a href=&quot;/images/elgato_hd/13.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/elgato_hd/13.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-16&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 16:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You should see the Elgato Game Capture HD. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click on it, and it will prompt you for a name.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;a href=&quot;/images/elgato_hd/14.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/elgato_hd/14.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Notice the name is already Elgato Game Capture HD. Just click ok&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;a href=&quot;/images/elgato_hd/15.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/elgato_hd/15.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-17-test&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 17: TEST&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Congratulations, everything should be setup and working now. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click on the “Preview button”. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The OBS preview window will come up, and you should see this: &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;a href=&quot;/images/elgato_hd/16.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/elgato_hd/16.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;After a few seconds, you should see your game on screen. You TV may flicker at this time as well. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you do not see your game, you may need to select a different input. To do this, right click on the Game Capture HD source, click on properties. Once you have the device window open, click on “Configure” (&lt;strong&gt;NOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: To configure the Game Capture HD device, the preview must be on).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Game Capture HD device option panel should come up, allowing you to change settings like resolution(Which feeds to OBS) and input.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-18-moar-testing&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 18: Moar testing!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Keep the preview open and running, and play a couple minutes. Keep an eye on OBS. If it shows warnings like “Taking to long to encode”, you have to lower the X264 preset. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If other errors come up, don’t be afraid to ask on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://obsproject.com/forum/&quot;&gt;OBS forums&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This is also the time to test your mic volume, add a webcam, add overlays and more.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-19-stream&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 19: Stream&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once you have setup the scenes and sources, stop the preview, and click on stream. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You are now live on Twitch! happy streaming.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This guide was written by Phil, Community Coordinator at Elgato Gaming. If you require support for your Elgato Game Capture HD please contact &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/ElgatoSupport&quot;&gt;@ElgatoSupport&lt;/a&gt; or open a ticket via the &lt;a href=&quot;http://help.elgato.com/customer/portal/emails/new&quot;&gt;Elgato Help Desk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitchtips.com/elgato-game-capture-hd-obs/&quot;&gt;How to setup the Elgato Game Capture HD in OBS&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Twitch Tips at &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitchtips.com&quot;&gt;Twitch Tips&lt;/a&gt; on June 28, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>


  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[HexChat Setup for Twitch Chat]]></title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://twitchtips.com/hexchat-guide/" />
    <id>https://twitchtips.com/hexchat-guide</id>
    <published>2014-06-20T00:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2014-06-20T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Twitch Tips</name>
      <uri>https://twitchtips.com</uri>
      <email>contact@twitchtips.com</email>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Connecting to Twitch IRC can be quite the task for those not knowledgeable with IRC client, check out how you can set yourself up connecting to Twitch chats using HexChat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;adding-a-network&quot;&gt;Adding a Network&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Navigate to HexChat &amp;gt; Network List (or press ctrl+s)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/images/hexchat_guide/settings.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/hexchat_guide/settings.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click &lt;strong&gt;Add&lt;/strong&gt; to add a new network. Name it whatever you desire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/images/hexchat_guide/networklist.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/hexchat_guide/networklist.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Double-click &lt;strong&gt;newserver/6667&lt;/strong&gt; and change it to read &lt;strong&gt;irc.twitch.tv/6667&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/images/hexchat_guide/edit1.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/hexchat_guide/edit1.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Untick &lt;strong&gt;Use global user information&lt;/strong&gt; (if it’s ticked) and enter your Twitch user name in the &lt;strong&gt;Nick name&lt;/strong&gt; field and your OAUTH token in the &lt;strong&gt;Password&lt;/strong&gt; field and click &lt;strong&gt;OK&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Not sure how to get an OAuth token? Check out this &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitchapps.com/tmi/&quot;&gt;token generator&lt;/a&gt; created by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/bgeorge&quot;&gt;@bGeorge&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/images/hexchat_guide/edit2.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/hexchat_guide/edit2.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note&lt;/em&gt; - You may tick &lt;strong&gt;Connect to this network automatically&lt;/strong&gt; to join twitch chat automatically when you start HexChat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/images/hexchat_guide/autoconnect.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/hexchat_guide/autoconnect.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now close the edit network window, select your newly created network and click &lt;strong&gt;Connect&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/images/hexchat_guide/connect.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/hexchat_guide/connect.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;joining-channels&quot;&gt;Joining Channels&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Standard IRC context applies here as above.  To join a channel simply type &lt;em&gt;/join #channelname&lt;/em&gt; in the dialogue box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;HexChat can be configured to join channels automatically as well.  To do this simply right click an already joined channel and tick &lt;strong&gt;Autojoin&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/images/hexchat_guide/autojoin.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/hexchat_guide/autojoin.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Written by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/GUIpsp&quot;&gt;@GUIpsp&lt;/a&gt; based on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitchtips.com/kvirc-guide/&quot;&gt;KVIRC setup guide&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/Izlsnizzt&quot;&gt;@Izlsnizzt&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitchtips.com/hexchat-guide/&quot;&gt;HexChat Setup for Twitch Chat&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Twitch Tips at &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitchtips.com&quot;&gt;Twitch Tips&lt;/a&gt; on June 20, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>


  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Multi-display Broadcasting (OBS Guide)]]></title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://twitchtips.com/multi-display/" />
    <id>https://twitchtips.com/multi-display</id>
    <published>2014-06-14T00:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2014-06-14T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Twitch Tips</name>
      <uri>https://twitchtips.com</uri>
      <email>contact@twitchtips.com</email>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This tutorial will guide you through the process of how you can use &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;OBS&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Open Broadcast Software&lt;/em&gt;) to broadcast using multiple displays ie: (Nvidia Surround/Eyefinity).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This is an &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;example&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; of how the default settings using &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Game Capture&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; in &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;OBS&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; would appear to you and your viewers. Using this guide will allow you to broadcast your center display.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/images/multi-display/1.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/multi-display/1.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 1:&lt;/strong&gt; Open OBS. At this point you should also open up the game you plan to broadcast and/or record and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;alt+tab&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 2:&lt;/strong&gt; Click on &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Settings&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Video&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/images/multi-display/2.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/multi-display/2.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 3:&lt;/strong&gt; Enter the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Custom Resolution Size&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; as your monitor size. In my case, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;1920x1080&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. You can also choose your &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Resolution Downscale&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/images/multi-display/3.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/multi-display/3.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 4:&lt;/strong&gt; Click on &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;OK&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 5:&lt;/strong&gt; Right click in the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sources&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; box and click &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Add&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Game Capture&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/images/multi-display/4.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/multi-display/4.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 6:&lt;/strong&gt; Click on Application &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;drop-down menu&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and choose the game you wish to broadcast. You may need to click on refresh if you’ve only just openend a game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/images/multi-display/5.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/multi-display/5.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 7:&lt;/strong&gt; Click &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;OK&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 8:&lt;/strong&gt; Now let’s see how it looks. Click on &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Preview&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/images/multi-display/6.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/multi-display/6.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now as you can see we’re now capturing the middle display. For the purpose of this tutorial I have Minecraft in window mode but it will work correctly in fullscreen. But you might want to remove the black bars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 9:&lt;/strong&gt; Click on the the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; you added. Then click &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Edit Scene&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/images/multi-display/7.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/multi-display/7.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 10:&lt;/strong&gt; Point your &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;cursor&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to the very edge of the game capture seeing the red border liness. While holding &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Shift&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. Drag your mouse down until you’ve filled the black bars. Repeat the process for the top.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/images/multi-display/8.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/multi-display/8.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And there you have it. If you followed these instructions correctly you should now be able to start broadcasting in a multi-display configuration (Nvidia Surround, Eyefinity Setup).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This article was written by Sammy. You can find Sammy on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/ImSammyTTV&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitch.tv/ImSammy&quot;&gt;Twitch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitchtips.com/multi-display/&quot;&gt;Multi-display Broadcasting (OBS Guide)&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Twitch Tips at &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitchtips.com&quot;&gt;Twitch Tips&lt;/a&gt; on June 14, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>


  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Protecting Yourself Online]]></title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://twitchtips.com/protecting-yourself/" />
    <id>https://twitchtips.com/protecting-yourself</id>
    <published>2014-05-24T00:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2014-05-24T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Twitch Tips</name>
      <uri>https://twitchtips.com</uri>
      <email>contact@twitchtips.com</email>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many or most of you will of heard of a DDoS attack during your time on the internet, whether it be on Twitch, a news site, reddit etc. DDoS stands for: Distributed Denial of Service. In its basic form it’s essentially a group of nodes (computers) sending useless data to your network and causing issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Believe it or not there are other users out there that will attempt to attack you with said method in order to generally annoy and harass you. Such attacks can cause your connection to drop (for extended periods or continously dropping ever x seconds depending on the strength of the attack).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-are-you-telling-me-this&quot;&gt;Why are you telling me this?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In some communities DDoS’ing is widely used and we want to help you ensure you protect yourself as best as possible with what resources are available to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In theory this guide cannot guarantee you’ll be safe from said attacks, but it’ll teach you how to prevent them as best as possible. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-how-do-i-do-this&quot;&gt;So how do I do this?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, essentially for someone to attack you or your network they’ll need an IP address, think of it like your internet street address - it’s unique to you (unless you’re using a public accessible WiFi etc).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Now generally, users IP addresses are supposed to be hidden or out of the general public view however there is multiple “exploits” throughout online services that allow others to extract the information they need, some of the popular methods are listed below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Peer-to-peer / VOIP (Some Games, Skype etc)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dumped Databases / Server Logs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Honeypots (IP Grabbing websites)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;There’s also more methods but they’re generally not much of an issue in the gaming community etc. For now we’ll go over the 3 listed on how they work and how you can best protect yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;peer-to-peer-p2p--voip&quot;&gt;Peer-to-peer (P2P) / VOIP&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some services such as Skype are known as VOIP applications, it basically means voice over the internet (IP). Now you may think due to Skype being such a big name you’d be safe - you’re not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Skype has a tendency to allow users to resolve your Skype handle and return an IP address. In the past this was extremely easy to do to anyone since anyone could query any handle and return an IP address - however since then they have added in a feature that disallows direct connections to users not on your Skype friends list. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Generally this enough for most people if they keep their Skype extremely private. But of course some people like to add anyone and everyone and even with the direct connection blocking enabled users on your friends lists can still resolve your IP address by simply querying it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;What’s the fix to this you may ask? There’s no real fix - you simply add an extra line of defense, in this case a HTTP / SOCKS5 proxy (you’ll want to prioritize SOCKS5 &amp;gt; HTTP).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Okay, so how do I setup this proxy?&lt;/strong&gt; Firstly you’ll want to direct yourself to Skype and click the Tools drop down, from there click Options and head to Advanced &amp;gt; Connection. You should see a screen like what is show below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/images/skype_connections.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/skype_connections.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Firstly you’re going to want to go ahead and enable “Allow direct connections to your contacts only”. This will present users outside of your Skype friends lists from querying your IP address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you’d like to know how to set up  a proxy for your Skype account or other internet services, simple follow &lt;a href=&quot;http://imgur.com/a/NpFdW&quot;&gt;this guide&lt;/a&gt; written by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/IncendiaryMedia&quot;&gt;Fire&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/images/skype_warning.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/skype_warning.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you don’t wish to set up a proxy for Skype or other services you use we highly recommend you keep your contacts absolutely limited to people you &lt;strong&gt;know&lt;/strong&gt; you can trust. If you add them to your contacts and they have malicious intentions there’s no stopping them from resolving your handle if you don’t have a proxy set up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It is also noteworthy you can use a VPN (virtual private network) to mask your actual IP address however VPN’s generally mask &lt;strong&gt;all of your traffic&lt;/strong&gt; rather than just Skype for example. A lot of VPN services have been banned through other users abusing them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dumped-databases--server-logs&quot;&gt;Dumped Databases / Server Logs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately it happens, there are people out there that will exploit, abuse and hack into services which you may use, there’s almost nothing you can do about it - it’s just part of the internet in general.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Unfortunately individuals that do decide to follow such activities also release privately held information on a regular basis such as databases and server logs which may contain your account details (username, e-mail, password hash, last used IP address, IP address registered with etc).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This information can and will be abused by individuals that stumble upon it. The best ways to combat this are listed below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you can help it, never use the same username or alias on multiple websites that aren’t related to your online streaming persona.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use different passwords for every website, &lt;strong&gt;never&lt;/strong&gt; use the same password for multiple websites - if it’s compromised via one website, it’s compromised for the rest you use.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Invest into a VPN or proxy service, this way websites you use will never actually see your real IP address therefore if they’re compromised you aren’t exposed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Other than the tips stated above, there’s not much else you can do - be careful what information you share and who you share it with. Knowledge is power and people will abuse that if they can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;honeypots-ip-grabbing-websites&quot;&gt;Honeypots (IP Grabbing websites)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honeypots in their purest form are websites, servers and services used to bait users into using them and then recording what they do, their information etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Essentially Honeypots are entities which you don’t want to be on the wrong side of. Their sole intention is information gathering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Why is this important to me you may ask? Well, unfortunately again there are users out there that will set up such services and attempt to bait you into clicking / using them such as IP grabbing websites, phishing websites and just general malicious services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If someone you don’t know (or in some cases do know) asks you to visit a website, connect to a server that you don’t recognize, think twice. What they’re sending you could be a trap, do some research beforehand if you’re curious but again, be careful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I’m not trying to suggest you be 100% paranoid about anything and everything people send you, but think twice before following through. It only takes one mistakes for them to cause you a tonne of grief.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Internet can be a scary place and as a streamer you may be targeted for whatever reason is humanly possible to comprehend. Yes, it sucks and it’s unfortunate - but don’t get too down on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Stay safe online, protect yourself and if you’re having problems with someone harassing you on Twitch send a report of them &lt;a href=&quot;http://help.twitch.tv/customer/portal/articles/725568-how-to-file-a-report&quot;&gt;following this method&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitchtips.com/protecting-yourself/&quot;&gt;Protecting Yourself Online&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Twitch Tips at &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitchtips.com&quot;&gt;Twitch Tips&lt;/a&gt; on May 24, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>


  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Greeter Bots]]></title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://twitchtips.com/greeter-bots/" />
    <id>https://twitchtips.com/greeter-bots</id>
    <published>2014-05-21T00:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2014-05-21T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Twitch Tips</name>
      <uri>https://twitchtips.com</uri>
      <email>contact@twitchtips.com</email>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Are Bots that welcome users to your channel causing you to lose viewers? Find out here!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;853&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/2wasHmMHRtI&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Interested in an in-depth post on Twitch Chat Bots? Check out &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitchtips.com/chat-moderation-bots/&quot;&gt;this other post&lt;/a&gt; by another Twitch Tips contributor!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This video was brought to you by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitch.tv/indie&quot;&gt;Indie&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You can also find Indie on:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/TheRealIndie&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/indiearmy&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitchtips.com/greeter-bots/&quot;&gt;Greeter Bots&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Twitch Tips at &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitchtips.com&quot;&gt;Twitch Tips&lt;/a&gt; on May 21, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>


  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chat moderation bots]]></title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://twitchtips.com/chat-moderation-bots/" />
    <id>https://twitchtips.com/chat-moderation-bots</id>
    <published>2014-05-19T00:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2014-05-19T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Twitch Tips</name>
      <uri>https://twitchtips.com</uri>
      <email>contact@twitchtips.com</email>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;bots---what-are-they&quot;&gt;1. Bots - what are they?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While having moderators in chat is nice, they are, in fact, human. &lt;br /&gt;
They make mistakes, have a reaction time that massively exceeds the time a computer takes to react to messages written in chat and occasionally need some sleep.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
For this reason, so called “Chat moderation robots” or simply “bots” have been created by third party developers.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
These can perform basic moderation tasks, such as timing out users automatically if they use offensive words in chat, as well as custom chat commands, which make the bot respond with information if a command is posted in chat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/images/bot_guide/image1.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/bot_guide/image1.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    	&lt;figcaption&gt;Example of a built-in command to create a custom command.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;when-and-why-should-i-get-a-bot&quot;&gt;2. When and why should I get a bot?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For very small channels, with low amount of viewers, a bot is not necessary. &lt;br /&gt;
Having a bot in a channel that is live once a week and averages 3 viewers just wastes resources on the bot- and chat servers.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
If you do not have a lot of viewers, you will probably not be in the need of a bot – consider expanding your viewership and getting a bot when it becomes a necessity, for example, if spammers keep posing a problem, or people keep asking the same questions over and over, that is a definite sign you want a bot.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Be careful with repeated commands however, if you are in a channel with 5 viewers and a bot keeps posting social media info every 2 minutes, that just gets obnoxious as time passes on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-bots-are-there-which-should-i-choose&quot;&gt;3. What bots are there? Which should I choose?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These questions are important to answer, yet impossible to answer completely.&lt;br /&gt;
There is a wide range of bots and reasons why you want a bot.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
To address the first question, I will try to give an overview over the 3 most commonly used bots:  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Xanbot, developed by Aaron ‘Xangold’ Clay, who is Twitch Staff as well&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Moobot, developed by Moocat, a Twitch Admin&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nightbot, developed by the NightDev team, the makers of BetterTTV&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These bots are all similar, yet optimized for different use cases. &lt;br /&gt;
Every channel can use each of the bots, but properly deciding which bot to use can make your life on Twitch a lot easier.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-basics&quot;&gt;The Basics&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While this does not hold true for every bot, most bots (including these three bots) can be controlled with commands that are posted in chat. 
These commands usually take the form of&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;html&quot;&gt;!&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;commandname&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;parameters&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For any bot, there are predefined commands, which allow you to make changes to commands and other settings the bot might provide. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Additionally, most bots allow for the creation of custom commands, which make the bot post a certain message in chat (see image below) and even have the bot automatically repeat the command to create a repeat the command every so often.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/images/bot_guide/image2.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/bot_guide/image2.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    	&lt;figcaption&gt;Example of a bot, reacting to a custom command.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The exact commands available differ greatly between the bots covered here, which is why I will not go into full detail about them - there are help pages and command lists for all of these bots.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Additionally, some bots even have a graphical interface (“GUI” or “dashboard”) to control the bots.&lt;br /&gt;
It simplifies the process of making changes to the bot without needing to know all the commands and how they work, since commands have to be entered exactly as they should to work properly, “something similar” will not be understood correctly by the bot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;nightbot&quot;&gt;Nightbot&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nightbot is a bot that specializes in ease of use and fun features, and thus is especially useful for small channels, but there is no limit to the size of channel that can use Nightbot (the second biggest stream on Twitch even uses Nightbot).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
It uses a freemium model, providing basic functionality for free and removing limitations if you donate to the NightDev team.&lt;br /&gt;
A full command list is found in the Nightbot dashboard.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Most prominent features:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A dashboard, which allows you to edit settings via &lt;a href=&quot;http://nightbot.tv&quot;&gt;http://nightbot.tv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Automated  moderation, consisting of timeouts for spammers and offensive chatters, with a wide range of settings for each type of spam&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Custom commands, with variables that allow you to put dynamic content to the commands, even trigger external URLs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Raffles – These allow you to select a random viewer for giveaways, viewer battles and similar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Votes/Polls – Have the viewers decide what game to play next, guess the winner of a game you are spectating or vote on which their favorite food is, or anything else that viewers should decide on &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The ability to allow other users (for example, some of your chat moderators) to access your dashboard. These people are called “Sub users” and have almost full access to your Nightbot dashboard&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can get Nightbot by creating an account at the Nightbot dashboard and clicking the “Join” button after logging in. Make sure to make Nightbot a moderator in your chat with  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;html&quot;&gt;/mod Nightbot
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;moobot&quot;&gt;Moobot&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A bot designed for ease-of-use, with a high-level dashboard from which you can edit all of the bots settings.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
One of the biggest benefits is its extreme speed and reliability, built to prevent spam by timing out users fast enough that users don’t even get to see bad messages, instead of removing them after a short duration.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
It is free to use, but certain features and restrictions require payment.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Partial list of features:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A dashboard, comparable to Nightbot’s dashboard at &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitch.moobot.tv&quot;&gt;http://twitch.moobot.tv&lt;/a&gt; that not just allows you to change the bot, but even allows you to run commands remotely&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Automated moderation tools, with lots of settings that allow you to customize how the bot reacts to all kinds of spam&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Custom commands, with the ability to display information about your steam username, current game, League of Legends runes and masteries, XBL gamertags, currently playing song, and much more&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Raffles, Polls&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The ability to allow other users (for example, some of your chat moderators) to access your dashboard. These people are called “Editors” within Moobot and have almost full access to your Moobot dashboard&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Welcome messages to new viewers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Features such as changing the bots username in chat, however at a price&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get Moobot, connect your Twitch account to the Moobot dashboard at &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitch.moobot.tv/&quot;&gt;http://twitch.moobot.tv/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A command list is found in the Moobot dashboard - however, you dont need that! Moobot can be entirely controlled via the dashboard. To use Moobot, you have to type&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;html&quot;&gt;/mod Moobot
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;xanbot&quot;&gt;Xanbot&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Out of the 3 bots covered in this article, Xanbot is the only one that does not have a dashboard at the time of this write-down and is completely controlled by chat commands.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
However, it excels at moderation thanks to its support for regular expressions, which make it harder to use and therefore, more focused on advanced users, providing them with the most powerful tools to keep spam low.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Xanbot is completely free to use for all users.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Some of Xanbot’s features:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sophisticated spam removal via the support of regular expressions on top of the basic spam filters that it essentially shares with Nightbot and Xanbot&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Custom commands and autoreplies, allowing the bot to react to messages that aren’t In the form of “!command”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Raffle, Polls&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Several utility commands, allowing you to display information on LoL runes, masteries, the weather and much more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can get Xanbot by going to &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitch.tv/xangold&quot;&gt;http://twitch.tv/xangold&lt;/a&gt; and typing &lt;code&gt;!join&lt;/code&gt; in chat. Afterwards, add Xanbot as a moderator in your channel with&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;html&quot;&gt;/mod Xanbot
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A complete command list for Xanbot can be found at &lt;a href=&quot;http://xangold.tv/help/&quot;&gt;http://xangold.tv/help/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;which-bot-to-choose&quot;&gt;4. Which Bot to Choose?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that we have covered the most common bots on Twitch, what bot should you use? Does it need to be one of these 3?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Both of these questions cannot be answered definitively. All of these bots are under constant development, improving their stability and feature set. If you have the necessity to add a bot to your stream, you can try them out, or just use whatever bot you know best.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
If you are new to bot usage, it is definitely suggested to use Nightbot or Moobot, which have a lot of similarities in their usage. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Nobody can tell you which bot to use in general, it completely depends on what you what the bot to do for you. But all of the bots above are great if used correctly.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Alternatively, there are other bots which have not been handled here, examples would be DeepBot, Ackbot, and custom made bots, often just made for a single channel.&lt;br /&gt;
In a lot of cases, these aren’t provided free of charge however or pose the problem of hosting – they require a server to be run on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;getting-support&quot;&gt;5. Getting Support&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using a bot can be complicated and hard to people who are new to moderation. &lt;br /&gt;
Thankfully, there are a lot of people giving support for the bot you decide to use! In the case of the 3 bots listed above, you can find support for&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Nightbot:&lt;/strong&gt; Tweet at &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/theNightbot&quot;&gt;https://twitter.com/theNightbot&lt;/a&gt; or use the support form on the Nightbot dashboard: &lt;a href=&quot;http://nightbot.tv/support&quot;&gt;http://nightbot.tv/support&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Moobot:&lt;/strong&gt; Tweet at &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/MoobotApp&quot;&gt;https://twitter.com/MoobotApp&lt;/a&gt; or ask in &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitch.tv/moobot&quot;&gt;http://twitch.tv/Moobot&lt;/a&gt;, I sometimes read that chat&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Xanbot:&lt;/strong&gt; Tweet at &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/xangold&quot;&gt;https://twitter.com/Xangold&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/xanbotupdates&quot;&gt;https://twitter.com/XanbotUpdates&lt;/a&gt; or just ask in &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitch.tv/xangold&quot;&gt;http://twitch.tv/Xangold&lt;/a&gt;, I usually stick around.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
However, keep in mind: we are all volunteers and may not have time to help at all points in time. Rule no.1 about getting support is patience. Leaving a support channel after a minute will most likely not give you an answer.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I myself give a lot of support for the bots I know well, mainly Xanbot and Moobot. Feel free to PM me on Twitch if you have specific questions!  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-dos-and-donts&quot;&gt;6. The DOs and DON’Ts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/images/bot_guide/image3.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/bot_guide/image3.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    	&lt;figcaption&gt;Example of a poorly configured bot.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the image above might be slightly overdone, it is a common thing that I regularly see in a lot of streams - people overuse a bots features, in a way that makes chat dominated by a bot.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
This is one of the key reasons why it is recommended not to use a bot for small channels.&lt;br /&gt;
A good rule you can apply to autoreplies and similar: if more than one automatically repeated bot message is visible at a single point in time, you are overdoing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;do&quot;&gt;DO:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keep spam by the bot low.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Have it post social media info if you feel like it, but do not overdo it.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Create custom commands!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
If a certain question gets asked very frequently, just make a command that provides the answer.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Get support!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
If you are unsure or new to bots and need help setting one up, there is always people with more experience than you who can help you out. (See part 5)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;dont&quot;&gt;DON’T:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Make your chat dominated by a bot (or several bots).&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
People coming your channel want to interact with you, not some computer program.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Rely on the bot for moderation.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
As soon as your stream gets going, make sure to (at least almost) always have moderators in your channel.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
While well-tweaked bot settings can essentially automatically moderate chat as well as you might like, there is always things that might not be caught.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Certain situations might require someone to adjust bot settings. For most bots, these settings can be changed by moderators, which makes having a moderator available very important at times.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Have too restrictive settings on the bot.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Why would a channel with 20 viewers have every person who posts a link timed out?&lt;br /&gt;
If there ever is a wave of spambots going on, the bot settings can be easily changed.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Make all commands mod-only, unless you are a huge channel.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Why?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
If you have a command that displays important information and someone asks for that info, a commonly seen thing is that channel regulars will ask the moderators to post the command!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
In what way would that be less annoying than giving them the ability to post the command themselves? A good solution to conquer bot spam in large channels is to make commands subscriber only.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This article was written by CBenni.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You can find CBenni on:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.twitter.com/CBenni_o&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://twitch.tv/Cbenni&quot;&gt;Twitch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitchtips.com/chat-moderation-bots/&quot;&gt;Chat moderation bots&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Twitch Tips at &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitchtips.com&quot;&gt;Twitch Tips&lt;/a&gt; on May 19, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>


  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[KVIRC Setup for Twitch Chat]]></title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://twitchtips.com/kvirc-guide/" />
    <id>https://twitchtips.com/kvirc-guide</id>
    <published>2014-05-16T00:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2014-05-16T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Twitch Tips</name>
      <uri>https://twitchtips.com</uri>
      <email>contact@twitchtips.com</email>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Connecting to Twitch IRC can be quite the task for those not knowledgeable with IRC client, check out how you can set yourself up connecting to Twitch chats using KVIRC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;adding-a-network&quot;&gt;Adding a Network&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Navigate to Settings &amp;gt; Configure Servers&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/images/kvirc_guide/settings.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/kvirc_guide/settings.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Select the &lt;strong&gt;New Network&lt;/strong&gt; icon in the top right and create a new network, I’ve named mine “Twitch”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/images/kvirc_guide/servers.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/kvirc_guide/servers.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next Select &lt;strong&gt;New Server&lt;/strong&gt; and enter &lt;em&gt;irc.twitch.tv&lt;/em&gt; in the &lt;strong&gt;Server&lt;/strong&gt; field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/images/kvirc_guide/servers_pt2.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/kvirc_guide/servers_pt2.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next click &lt;strong&gt;Advanced&lt;/strong&gt; and enter your Twitch user name in the &lt;strong&gt;Nickname&lt;/strong&gt; field and your OAUTH token in the &lt;strong&gt;Password&lt;/strong&gt; field and click &lt;strong&gt;OK&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Not sure how to get an OAuth token? Check out this &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitchapps.com/tmi/&quot;&gt;token generator&lt;/a&gt; created by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/bgeorge&quot;&gt;@bGeorge&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/images/kvirc_guide/login.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/kvirc_guide/login.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note&lt;/em&gt; - You may check &lt;strong&gt;Connect to this server at startup&lt;/strong&gt; to join the server automatically when you start KVIRC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/images/kvirc_guide/connection.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/kvirc_guide/connection.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now simply click &lt;strong&gt;Connect Now&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/images/kvirc_guide/servers_pt3.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/kvirc_guide/servers_pt3.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;joining-channels&quot;&gt;Joining Channels&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Standard IRC context applies here as above.  To join a channel simply type &lt;em&gt;/join #channelname&lt;/em&gt; in the dialogue box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;KVIRC can be configured to join channels automatically as well.  To do this select the &lt;strong&gt;Join Channels&lt;/strong&gt; tab in your &lt;strong&gt;Server Details&lt;/strong&gt; page.  Add channels by typing the channel name in the dialogue box and clicking &lt;strong&gt;Add&lt;/strong&gt; (Don’t forget the #hashtag).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/images/kvirc_guide/servers_pt4.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/kvirc_guide/servers_pt4.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/Izlsnizzt&quot;&gt;@Izlsnizzt&lt;/a&gt; for writing this guide on connecting to Twitch Chat via KVIRC. &lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitchtips.com/kvirc-guide/&quot;&gt;KVIRC Setup for Twitch Chat&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Twitch Tips at &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitchtips.com&quot;&gt;Twitch Tips&lt;/a&gt; on May 16, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>


  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Poor Advertising]]></title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://twitchtips.com/poor-advertising/" />
    <id>https://twitchtips.com/poor-advertising</id>
    <published>2014-05-15T00:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2014-05-15T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Twitch Tips</name>
      <uri>https://twitchtips.com</uri>
      <email>contact@twitchtips.com</email>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;What is the worst way to try and get viewers? Find out with this quick video!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;853&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/xaPZVTdqItg&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This video was brought to you by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitch.tv/indie&quot;&gt;Indie&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You can also find Indie on:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/TheRealIndie&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/indiearmy&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitchtips.com/poor-advertising/&quot;&gt;Poor Advertising&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Twitch Tips at &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitchtips.com&quot;&gt;Twitch Tips&lt;/a&gt; on May 15, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>


  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The BetterTTV Extension]]></title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://twitchtips.com/betterttv/" />
    <id>https://twitchtips.com/betterttv</id>
    <published>2014-05-01T00:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2014-05-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Twitch Tips</name>
      <uri>https://twitchtips.com</uri>
      <email>contact@twitchtips.com</email>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;BetterTTV enhances Twitch with new features, bug fixes, and reduced clutter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;features&quot;&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chat Tweaks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blacklist spam&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chat field history&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Highlight words and phrases&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pinned highlighted words and phrases&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Improved connection monitoring &amp;amp; server selection&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Resizeable (drag-able) chat&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Show or remove deleted messages&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Split chat lines and paragraph indentation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Unban all users with &lt;code&gt;/massunban&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Username color calculation (prevents hard-to-read names)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Username &amp;amp; emote tab completion&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Enhanced moderator cards and keybinds&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Anon Chat (hidden in viewer list)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chat image link previews on hover&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Broadcast Dashboard
       - Prioritizes chat, and auto-updates channel statistics&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Darken Twitch
       - A slick, grey theme which will make you love Twitch even more&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Notifications
       - On-site and desktop notifications when people send you messages, mention you in chat, and when channels you follow go live &amp;amp; more!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;guide-to-setting-up-betterttv&quot;&gt;Guide to setting up BetterTTV&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Download it from the specific link for your browser:  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/betterttv/ajopnjidmegmdimjlfnijceegpefgped?hl=en&quot;&gt;Chrome&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nightdev.com/betterttv/betterttvfirefox.xpi&quot;&gt;Firefox&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nightdev.com/betterttv/betterttvopera.nex&quot;&gt;Opera&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nightdev.com/betterttv/betterttvsafari.safariextz&quot;&gt;Safari&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nightdev.com/betterttv/betterttvie.exe&quot;&gt;Internet Explorer&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nightdev.com/betterttv/betterttv.user.js&quot;&gt;UserScript for GreaseMonkey / Tamper Monkey&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Once you have installed it navigate to a TwitchTV channel. Click the Cog And Click BetterTTV Settings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;a href=&quot;/images/customization_guide/bttv_howto_settings.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/customization_guide/bttv_howto_settings.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Then choose your settings, below are my custom settings which I think are the best way to do it but feel free to try everything out!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;a href=&quot;/images/customization_guide/bttv_custom_settings.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/customization_guide/bttv_custom_settings.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;chroma-keying-chat-deprecated&quot;&gt;Chroma Keying Chat (deprecated)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;*(BTTV Black Chat (Chroma Key) feature is deprecated in favor of &lt;a href=&quot;https://nightdev.com/kapchat/&quot;&gt;KapChat&lt;/a&gt;, and will eventually be removed.*&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For streamers who want to Chroma key the chat onto your screen without a background so it goes over games can follow the next part.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;First of all Pop-out the chat so you have it in a second window (The settings gear –&amp;gt; Pop-out Chat –&amp;gt; When the chat pops out do the same again –&amp;gt; Settings Gear –&amp;gt; Chroma Key)
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;When you have opened it and Clicked on the chroma key setting you chat should look something like this:
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/images/customization_guide/bttv_custom_chromakey.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/customization_guide/bttv_custom_chromakey.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;What you then want to do is capture it in your capture program (OBS, XSplit ETC..)
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;When you have the window selected and your region selected pick black #000000 To be keyed out.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;It should look something like this.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/images/customization_guide/bttv_custom_ingame.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/customization_guide/bttv_custom_ingame.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Write up by &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/GavXD&quot;&gt;Gav&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://nightdev.com&quot;&gt;NightDev, LLC&lt;/a&gt; for their amazing add-on!
&lt;a href=&quot;http://twitch.tv/lirik&quot;&gt;Lirik&lt;/a&gt; used as an example for chat screenshots!&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitchtips.com/betterttv/&quot;&gt;The BetterTTV Extension&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Twitch Tips at &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitchtips.com&quot;&gt;Twitch Tips&lt;/a&gt; on May 01, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>


  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Twitch Teams]]></title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://twitchtips.com/twitch-teams/" />
    <id>https://twitchtips.com/twitch-teams</id>
    <published>2014-04-30T00:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2014-04-30T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Twitch Tips</name>
      <uri>https://twitchtips.com</uri>
      <email>contact@twitchtips.com</email>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Twitch teams. That feeling of being a part of something special with your fellow broadcasters. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A sense of belonging sharing a common bond within the vast awesomeness of Twitch. But what purpose do they really serve and how can they help you as a streamer?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Let’s get started with the basics first though!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-a-twitch-team&quot;&gt;What is a Twitch Team?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Twitch team is a grouping of streamers who voluntarily join upon being invited by a team maker. Typically these people have a common goal, mindset, game, or approach to streaming that binds them together under their team banner. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It’s a multi-way endorsement that says to Twitch viewers: these streams I approve of and they approve of me, so check them out!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-does-a-twitch-team-look-like&quot;&gt;What does a Twitch Team look like?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If someone is a part of at least one team, you’ll be able to see this under their stream title. Like so:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/images/twitch-teams.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/twitch-teams.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;who-can-make-a-team&quot;&gt;Who can make a team?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teams can only be created by a partnered streamer (no sub button required!). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The partner emails partnersupport in order to request a team. Once approved, the partner can then go to; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Settings&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click “Channels &amp;amp; Videos”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Scroll down to “Teams”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click “Edit” team (or just add your team url name to this: http://www.twitch.tv/team/YOURNAMEHERE/edit) and add members, manage the order in which members will appear, and add art to spiff the main-page up. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You can add a featured channel to this main-page, review the archives, as well as review stats and revenue for any team member that has enabled sharing these features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;are-there-any-minimum-or-maximum-for-members-on-a-team&quot;&gt;Are there any minimum or maximum for members on a team?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nope! You are free to have as exclusive or as populated of a team as you like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;is-there-a-limit-for-how-many-teams-someone-can-join&quot;&gt;Is there a limit for how many teams someone can join?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nope! Commit to a singular meaningful favorite or collect them like Pokémon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-do-you-join-a-team&quot;&gt;How do you join a team?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To join a team follow below instructions;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Go to your Settings&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click “Channels &amp;amp; Videos”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Scroll down to “Teams”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Select “Accept” on an invite.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The three options you also have are to share your stats (partner only), your revenue (advertising, partner only), and to set a certain team - if you’re part of more than one - as your featured team under your stream title.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The revenue option allows the team owner to see your revenue if you are a Twitch Partner. However, your revenue remains tied to your account only and is not shared with the team owner or the team in any other way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-do-you-leave-a-team&quot;&gt;How do you leave a team?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To leave a team follow below instructions;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Go to your Settings&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click “Channels &amp;amp; Videos”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Scroll down to “Teams”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Select “Remove” for the team you wish to leave &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(Note: read below for the social side of this action)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;would-you-like-to-know-more&quot;&gt;Would you like to know more?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are finer points of team dynamics as well. Read on if you need more on the social aspects of being in or running a team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-benefits-can-being-in-a-team-really-provide&quot;&gt;What benefits can being in a team really provide?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some teams are not active in cross-promotion or pushing a particular brand. These sorts of teams are quite dormant for networking and therefore do not provide much benefit to the team members in terms of channel growth. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;These sorts of teams might prefer to show an exclusive circle of friends or a collection of streamers under a network that are not tied together on any other aspect. Often though, to be in a team means you are there to promote your fellow team-mates as well as be promoted by them. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It’s a mutually beneficial sort of thing. I’d suggest you don’t expect much if you aren’t willing to pitch in. Remember, this micro-community only has as much value as you and your fellow team-mates place in it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;is-it-better-or-worse-to-be-on-more-than-one-team&quot;&gt;Is it better or worse to be on more than one team?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From what I’ve seen, there are some people who stick to only one team and focus only on that. There are others who are in 3+ teams which all share roughly the same viewership; and in this sort of situation, most streamers in each team often play the same games. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Therefore, joining too many teams in the same game community is only cannibalizing your own cross-team exposure potential. At the same time, your channel shows up on more team pages and potentially brings more new eyes to your page. The choice is yours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;when-should-i-join-a-team&quot;&gt;When should I join a team?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no certain ‘right time’ to join a team. It’s entirely up to when you feel comfortable. If you’re thinking you wish to try for a career as a streamer, then you might want to be more careful and take longer to consider your options than if you merely enjoy streaming as a hobby. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Ask yourself a few simple questions before committing: do you know all of the streamers on the team? Do you have any personal discomfort with any current members? Do you enjoy watching most of the members? Are these other channels the sort you’d proudly send your own viewers to? Being on a team means to your viewers that you approve of the channels under the same team name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;is-it-better-to-make-my-own-team-or-join-another&quot;&gt;Is it better to make my own team or join another?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That depends on a few aspects of your channel and how much free time you have. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Managing a team doesn’t take THAT much extra work, but does take some, as you need to create and maintain relationships with the members you’ve invited (you should do this even if you’re just a member), help promote their streams and set an example for them (chances are they are all smaller than you if you’re the team creator), and of course, it’s best if you put effort into creating a logo and art for the main-page as well. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Art isn’t required, but if you want a professional team image, then you’ll prioritize getting branding done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But maybe you aren’t interested in doing all of that management or maybe you don’t feel it’s for you due to time requirements or whatever other reason. If that’s the case, then simply joining another team might be better for you. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Joining another team means you still ought to cross-promote and be considerate to your fellow team-mates, but there is far less work involved and less potential responsibility&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Or - if neither of these options appeal to you - you can simply ‘lonewolf’ it on Twitch and avoid teams altogether! There are small and big streamers that do not have a team and are not part of someone else’s. The choice is yours. Networking is possible even without joining a team anyhow - so don’t feel obligated for the sake of your channel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-do-i-do-if-i-want-to-leave-a-team-whats-the-most-professional-way-to-do-so&quot;&gt;What do I do if I want to leave a team? What’s the most professional way to do so?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember that you are your brand on Twitch. Whatever manner you conduct yourself in might have an impact on your channel as a whole and might follow you for some time. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Clear and professional communication is best. I’d suggest messaging the team owner and leaving them a short and polite note that you appreciated your experience with the team but you feel it’s time to move on and you wish them the best. Easy peasy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This article was written by the wonderful Shannon (AKA: ShannonZKiller).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I am the community manager/partner for a streamer named Sacriel, and am also a Twitch Admin. You can expect community related posts from me here from time to time. Have a suggestion or request for a topic you’d like to know more on? Put it in a comment below!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find Shannon at the following places around the web!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.twitter.com/ShannonZKiller&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitch.tv/ShannonZKiller&quot;&gt;Twitch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/ShannonZKiller&quot;&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitch.tv/team/the42nd&quot;&gt;42nd On Twitch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitch.tv/Sacriel&quot;&gt;Sacriel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitchtips.com/twitch-teams/&quot;&gt;Twitch Teams&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Twitch Tips at &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitchtips.com&quot;&gt;Twitch Tips&lt;/a&gt; on April 30, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>


  

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[XSplit Setup]]></title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://twitchtips.com/xsplit-setup/" />
    <id>https://twitchtips.com/xsplit-setup</id>
    <published>2014-04-18T00:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2014-04-18T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Twitch Tips</name>
      <uri>https://twitchtips.com</uri>
      <email>contact@twitchtips.com</email>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;XSplit Broadcaster is one of the most popular broadcasting programs on Twitch and comes highly recommended. XSplit Broadcaster is considered an all-in-one solution as it allows the broadcaster to edit their stream with multiple camera shots, graphical overlays, chroma key, and picture-in-picture effects, as well as encoding the video feed with highly flexible range of quality options.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
(NOTE: Not to be confused with XSplit Gamecaster)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;key-features&quot;&gt;Key Features&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Easy setup: Login with your Twitch account and let the built-in wizard setup your optimum stream settings. You will be live on Twitch in less than 5 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use multiple scenes: Add and edit multiple video sources such as desktop screen capture, gamesource capture, titles, webcams, capture cards and much more.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Simple Audio Mixer: Capture computer and microphone audio simultaneously. Audio sources can be delayed to match capture card latency.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Twitch Ingest Point Tester: Always find the best location on the Twitch network to broadcast to wherever you are.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;download-xsplit&quot;&gt;Download XSplit&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.xsplit.com/twitchtv/SignUp&quot;&gt;here to create a free XSplit account&lt;/a&gt; and download the XSplit software.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
XSplit comes in a variety of Free, Personal and Premium versions, each with its own advantages. Please refer to the XSplit site for up-to-date information on its current status.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;getting-started-with-xsplit&quot;&gt;Getting Started with XSplit&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After finishing this guide, there’s more information available in the XSplit Beginner’s Guide on YouTube.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-1-adding-sources&quot;&gt;Step 1) Adding Sources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For PC games, you have two choices on how to capture your gameplay. Either by capturing the screen region, or by achieving a direct feed via game source (only available in XSplit Personal and Premium).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The screenshot below details where you can find the dropdown menu to add sources;  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/images/xsplit_guide/settings.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/xsplit_guide/sources.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;screen-region-method&quot;&gt;Screen Region Method&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Go to Add &amp;gt; Add Screen Region.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Select the region of your desktop you’d like XSplit to capture by left clicking somewhere in the game window. You can also click the desktop or task bar to select the entire monitor.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The selected area appears in your XSplit window for further editing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;game-source-method-requires-xsplit-personal-or-premium&quot;&gt;Game Source Method (Requires XSplit Personal or Premium)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Games that utilize the DirectX or OpenGL platform can be enabled for direct capture, or Game Source. This sometimes results in better performance when compared to the screen region method and supports games in fullscreen mode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Go to Add &amp;gt; Add Game and select the .exe of the game you’d like to capture.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The selected game appears in your XSplit window for further editing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;capture-device-xbox-playstation-3-webcam-etc&quot;&gt;Capture Device (Xbox, PlayStation 3, Webcam, etc)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Go to Add &amp;gt; Add Camera.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Select either the capture device or webcam you’d like to use.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The selected device appears in your XSplit window for further editing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-2-understanding-xsplit-audio&quot;&gt;Step 2) Understanding XSplit Audio&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;xsplit-accepts-two-audio-sources-simultaneously&quot;&gt;XSplit accepts two audio sources simultaneously.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Windows 7 default playback device (desktop audio) essentially what comes out of the default speaker&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The currently selected microphone in the XSplit user settings under Tools &amp;gt; General Settings &amp;gt; General Tab &amp;gt; Audio&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;volume-control&quot;&gt;Volume Control&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Each audio source has its own volume that you can manually adjust - right-click the source and use the properties provided&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sources that tend to have audio settings include webcams, capture cards, video files, etc&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Using the Windows Audio Mixer, typically located at the bottom-right hand corner of your Windows taskbar, you can adjust the volumes of these devices individually&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: All audio sources added in XSplit rely on your Windows 7 Default Device for audio to your stream. In other words, if you can hear it over your speakers, your audience will too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-3-selecting-quality-options-and-broadcasting&quot;&gt;Step 3) Selecting Quality Options and Broadcasting&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;basic-broadcast-settings&quot;&gt;Basic Broadcast Settings&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Go to Broadcast and click the right side gear symbol for your Twitch channel.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click the Wizard button in the lower left corner and follow the two steps. When it’s done probing your internet speed and computer hardware, click Finish to use the recommended settings.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Optional: View &amp;gt; Scale Viewport &amp;gt; 50.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Feel free to adjust the wizard settings based upon your own personal preferences and experience broadcasting to Twitch. You can also seek out tips in the XSplit community forum.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-4-go-live-and-interact-with-your-audience&quot;&gt;Step 4) Go live and interact with your audience!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;connecting-to-twitch&quot;&gt;Connecting to Twitch&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Go to Broadcast &amp;gt; Twitch Username.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Open your web browser and go to &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitch.tv/broadcast/dashboard&quot;&gt;http://twitch.tv/broadcast/dashboard&lt;/a&gt; to view both your channel and your chat window.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This post is a modified and re-designed version of Xangold’s original post on the official Twitch Helpdesk.	
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Thanks to him for putting so much effort into the original!	&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.twitter.com/xangold&quot;&gt;Xangold&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://help.twitch.tv/customer/portal/articles/733542-xsplit&quot;&gt;Original Post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Also thanks to fellow &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitch.tv/pipe&quot;&gt;Twitch Admin PIPe&lt;/a&gt; for sending me over a screenshot to demonstrate .. sources.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitchtips.com/xsplit-setup/&quot;&gt;XSplit Setup&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Twitch Tips at &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitchtips.com&quot;&gt;Twitch Tips&lt;/a&gt; on April 18, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>


  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[OBS Setup]]></title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://twitchtips.com/obs-setup/" />
    <id>https://twitchtips.com/obs-setup</id>
    <published>2014-04-18T00:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2014-04-18T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Twitch Tips</name>
      <uri>https://twitchtips.com</uri>
      <email>contact@twitchtips.com</email>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;getting-started&quot;&gt;Getting Started&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After downloading OBS, navigate to your settings by clicking Settings &amp;gt; Settings. A screenshot demonstrating this is below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/images/obs_guide/settings.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/obs_guide/settings.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;general-settings&quot;&gt;General Settings&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Select your language, and set a profile name.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/images/obs_guide/general.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/obs_guide/general.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;encoding&quot;&gt;Encoding&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;video-encoding&quot;&gt;Video Encoding&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Check “Use CBR”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Check “Enable CBR padding”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Max bitrate should be 3300 or 80% of your upload throughput, whichever is lower. Recommended bitrates for different resolutions are listed below.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Buffer Size is recommended to be equal to the max bitrate. Setting this lower will have the encoder closer to the targeted bitrate. We do not recommend changing this unless you know what you are doing. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; 
​Recommended bitrate for 1080p: 3000-3500&lt;br /&gt;
Recommended bitrate for 720p: 1800-2500&lt;br /&gt;
Recommended bitrate for 480p: 900-1200&lt;br /&gt;
Recommended bitrate for 360p: 600-800&lt;br /&gt;
Recommended bitrate for 240p: Up to 500  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;audio-encoding&quot;&gt;Audio Encoding&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We recommend AAC with a bitrate of 64-128, although this is up to personal preference and bandwidth constraints&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your encoding tab should now look a little something like below;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/images/obs_guide/encoding.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/obs_guide/encoding.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;broadcast-settings&quot;&gt;Broadcast Settings&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mode: Live stream&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Streaming Service: Twitch/Justin.tv&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Server: Closest geographical server.
If you are having issues with dropped frames, and you are sure your throughput and CPU are sufficient, try changing this.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Play Path/Stream Key: Go to your Dashboard and click the “Stream Key” tab. From here you can show your key by clicking said button. (&lt;strong&gt;Caution:&lt;/strong&gt; Do not show your stream key publicly).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/images/obs_guide/stream_key.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/obs_guide/stream_key.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Autoreconnect: Recommended checked.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Auto-Reconnect Timeout: 10 seconds&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Delay: 0, but if you need delay set locally you can do this to prevent “ghosting.” We do NOT recommend delay.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Minimize Network Impact: Unchecked. If you are an advanced user, or are having issues with your network settings, use this setting.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dashboard Link: http://www.twitch.tv/dashboard or blank.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Save to file: We HIGHLY recommend you keep local recordings on your computer as we make changes to our VOD storage, to ensure you always have easy access to your broadcasts.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Keep recording if live stream stops: Again, HIGHLY recommended you keep this enabled just in case you get disconnected, you’ll have a local recording to share later on&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;File Path: Select a file path for where you want to save your local files. Not needed if you do not save a local file.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Start Stream Hotkey: Custom key to start stream with.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stop Stream Hotkey: Custom key to stop stream with. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An example of what this would look like is below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/images/obs_guide/broadcast.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/obs_guide/broadcast.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;video-settings&quot;&gt;Video Settings&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Video Adapter should be set by default. If you have more than one, select the adapter you are playing your game on.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Base resolution typically is your monitors resolution. You can alternatively select a monitor to default this.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Resolution Downscale is the resolution that you send our servers. Lower resolutions will consume less bandwidth overall, and use much less processing power. (&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; Refer back to the encoding section to get the bitrate for a downscaled resolution)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Filter should be “Bilinear” unless you have issues with blurring in your downscaling. Bicubic and Lanczos are both supported, but will take additional processing.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;FPS is recommended to be 30. Note that 720p at 60 frames per second for some games will look better than low bitrate 1080p at 30 FPS.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Aero is recommended to be disabled only if you are using monitor or screen capture. (Do not turn off Aero if you are using layered windows, window capture, or game capture. Windows 8 cannot disable aero)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/images/obs_guide/video.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/obs_guide/video.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;audio-settings&quot;&gt;Audio Settings&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Desktop Audio Device: We recommend that this be set to your “Default” playback device. To change this, right click on your volume slider, then click playback devices. Then, right click on the audio device you’d like to make default and select “Set as Default Device.” Two images will show that process below:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;half&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/images/obs_guide/audio-one.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/obs_guide/audio-one.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/images/obs_guide/audio-two.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/obs_guide/audio-two.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Microphone/Auxiliary device: Set this to your headset or microphone if you have one.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use Push to talk: Set this if you want push to talk set to a custom key.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Push to talk delay: Time after key is released and OBS is still recording your mic.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mute/Unmute mic hotkey: User preferred hotkey to toggle mute settings for the Microphone/Auxiliary device.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mute/Unmute Desktop Hotkey: User preferred hotkey to toggle mute settings for the Desktop Audio Device.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Force Microphone/Auxiliary to Mono: If you want this to only use one channel. We do not recommend this.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Desktop Boost (multiple): Force OBS to boost your desktop audio. 1 is “100%”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mic/Aux Boost (multiple): Force OBS to boost your microphone audio. 1 is “100%”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mic Time Offset (ms): Default 0. Use this if you have sync issues. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An example of this page filled out is below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/images/obs_guide/audio.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/obs_guide/audio.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;advanced&quot;&gt;Advanced&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use multithreaded Optimizations: Checked&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Process Priority Class: Normal. Changing this higher will make OBS get CPU before other programs and can cause lag on many systems.
Scene Buffering Time (ms): 400&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Disable encoding while previewing: Unchecked unless you have lag while previewing your stream.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Allow other modifiers on hotkeys: Checked Video&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;x264 CPU Preset: This will set the encoding level. We recommend “veryfast” unless you have no bandwidth and beastly computer. Then, set it to be slower. Warning: setting your stream to a lower setting when at a high resolution is very CPU intensive.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;x264 Encoding profile: This setting changes what profile you record on. Some devices (notably tablets and phones) may have issues with decoding streams with “high” profiles, so we recommend main if you want to have the highest compatibility at the sacrifice of some quality.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use CFR: Checked [newer versions may not need this!]&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Custom x264 Encoder Settings: Default (blank)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Keyframe Interval: Set this to 2&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Allow 61-120 FPS entry in video settings: Unchecked. We don’t recommend users going above 60FPS for any game.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use Quicksync: If you have certain Intel processors (Sandy Bridge/Ivy Bridge), you can use this alternative method of encoding to use less CPU (it will use the hardware video encoder on your integrated GPU). There are quality differences due to the change of encoding. This nullifies x264 presets, but you can set the custom encoding settings if you want by checking “use custom x264 settigns for Quick Sync”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use Nvidia NVENC: Similar to quicksync, this uses an alternative encoding method, with quality differences (usually lower at the same bitrate) due to the change of encoding. There are several presets you can choose from with this using the NVENC Preset dropdown.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sub-options of Use Quick Sync and Use custom x264 settings for QSV should remain unchecked.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;audio&quot;&gt;Audio&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Force desktop audio to use timestamps as a base for audio time: Check this if you are having problems with syncing only.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Global audio Time Offset (ms): Set this to the number of ms you’d like to offset this to. We recommend 0 unless having issues with sync.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use Mic QPC timestamps: Use this only if having sync issues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;network&quot;&gt;Network&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bind to Interface: Default. You can select another network adapter here if you need to.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Automatic low latency mode: Check this only if you’ve talked to a OBS developer or Twitch staff as very few users would need this.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Latency tuning factor: Set this only if you’ve talked to a OBS developer or Twitch staff as very few users would need this. ​An example of what this would look like for a user is below:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/images/obs_guide/advanced.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/obs_guide/advanced.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;microphone-noise-gate&quot;&gt;Microphone Noise Gate&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This setting allows users to set an automatic threshold for their mic being turned on and off. You can select the decibel level of the Close and Open thresholds here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Attack Time: This is the time it takes for your mic to “spin up” to reach hold to output. You generally do not modify this.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hold time(ms) how long the gate will stay open after it falls below threshold. You generally do not modify this.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Release time: Inverse of attack time. You generally do not modify this. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our recommended “off” settings are found below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/images/obs_guide/noise-gate.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/obs_guide/noise-gate.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This about sums it up for the broadcaster technical settings, time to have a break, get a cup of coffee and we’ll have another post up soon with the source and scenes side of OBS (the fun stuff).	&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This post is a modified and re-designed version of Xangold’s original post on the official Twitch Helpdesk.	
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Thanks to him for putting so much effort into the original!	&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.twitter.com/xangold&quot;&gt;Xangold&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://help.twitch.tv/customer/portal/articles/1262922-open-broadcaster-software&quot;&gt;Original Post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitchtips.com/obs-setup/&quot;&gt;OBS Setup&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Twitch Tips at &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitchtips.com&quot;&gt;Twitch Tips&lt;/a&gt; on April 18, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>


  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Grey Screen Issue]]></title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://twitchtips.com/grey-screen/" />
    <id>https://twitchtips.com/grey-screen</id>
    <published>2014-04-17T00:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2014-04-17T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Twitch Tips</name>
      <uri>https://twitchtips.com</uri>
      <email>contact@twitchtips.com</email>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Got the issue where you can only see a grey screen with the Twitch logo centered in the middle? Well, here’s how to fix that issue!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The reason(s) you may be getting this issue is due to one of the following;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Javascript being disabled&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Extension causing javascript errors&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Firewall and / or Security software blocking JS execution&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Malware&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;DNS Issues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s start with the simple stuff, depending on the browser you’re using follow the relevant instructions below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;disabled-javascript&quot;&gt;Disabled Javascript&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;google-chrome&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go to: Settings &amp;gt; Privacy &amp;gt; Content settings &amp;gt; Javascript&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;From here make sure “Allow all sites to run JavaScript” is selected&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;Once you’re sure, click “Done”  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mozilla-firefox&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the URL / Address bar type: about:config and proceed to press enter &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;You may see a “warranty” screen, simply click the button saying “I’ll be careful, I promise!”&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;Once you’re in, type “javascript.enabled” into the search bar below the URL bar &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;Once you see the “javascript.enabled” preference, make sure the assigned value is “true” and not “false”. If it’s false simply right click and hit the “toggle option”. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;extensions&quot;&gt;Extensions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve made sure JavaScript is enabled on your browser and you’re still getting the grey screen, its time to check extensions!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;Firstly, lets test something - in your browser open up an incognito window (don’t lie, you know what that is) and try loading Twitch. Do you still get the same error?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;If so your problem isn’t likely to be an extension (make sure by checking extensions the browser allows to run in incognito mode - if you see no active extensions in incognito move down to the next section).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;If you did manage to load Twitch successfully then your perpetrator is likely an extension, go to your extension listings and make sure to disable all extensions.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;Now try to load Twitch again, if it works you can begin to enable extensions one by one until you find the one that is causing the issue and remove it from your installed extensions.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Still not working, lets move onto anti-virus / security software potentially blocking JS from being executed etc&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;anti-virus--security-software&quot;&gt;Anti-Virus / Security Software&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s hundreds of anti-virus and security software programs out there so it’s practically impossible for me to list every single one with detailed instructions on what to do.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;Simply, you’re looking for browser, network or web protection that allows you to configure the level of security the software will attempt to abide by.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;If you can, try to disable any firewall or web protection for a couple of minutes and try loading Twitch, still getting the issue? If not then you’re perpetrator is somewhere within those security settings, fiddle around and let us know how you fixed it so we can keep others up to date!  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;malware&quot;&gt;Malware&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The part we all didn’t want to get to; Malware can be very annoying, sophisticated and a general pain in the ass to deal with. However, we have some wonderful tools available to us!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;My advice is to install AdwCleaner and Malwarebytes and scan for any malware / adware or general horribleness lurking on your PC.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;Below are links to said tools, please let us know in the comments if you do manage to find anything so we can keep others up to date!  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.malwarebytes.org/&quot;&gt;MalwareBytes - Free Anti-Malware &amp;amp; Internet Security Software&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bleepingcomputer.com/download/adwcleaner/&quot;&gt;[Bleeping Computer] AdwCleaner&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dns-issues&quot;&gt;DNS Issues&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently its been noted that DNS issues on the user end may cause an issue reaching the CDN for Twitch. If you already know how to altar your DNS you can simply change to either of the following DNS providers.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;google&quot;&gt;Google&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8.8.8.8
&lt;br /&gt;8.8.4.4&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;opendns&quot;&gt;OpenDNS&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;208.67.222.222
&lt;br /&gt;208.67.220.220&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you’re not sure on how to change your DNS settings simply follow guide provided on Twitch’s help desk located &lt;a href=&quot;http://help.twitch.tv/customer/portal/articles/1444294-how-to-switch-your-dns&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; (PC) or this Mac guide &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.macinstruct.com/node/434&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; (Mac).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully you managed to get the problem dealt with using this blog post, if not - keep trying. You may of just missed something simple. Let us know how you get on in the comments.   &lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitchtips.com/grey-screen/&quot;&gt;Grey Screen Issue&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Twitch Tips at &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitchtips.com&quot;&gt;Twitch Tips&lt;/a&gt; on April 17, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>


  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Donation panels (Paypal)]]></title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://twitchtips.com/donation-panels-paypal/" />
    <id>https://twitchtips.com/donation-panels-paypal</id>
    <published>2014-04-14T00:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2014-04-14T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Twitch Tips</name>
      <uri>https://twitchtips.com</uri>
      <email>contact@twitchtips.com</email>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;People seem to always ask how to set up a donation button / panel on their channel for Twitch. The most confusing part for most is setting up the donation “button”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This tutorial will go through the entire process from logging into PayPal to getting your donation panel set up. What you need in order to follow this tutorial is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PayPal Account (make one if you haven’t got one)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pre-made donation button / image for the panels (max width &amp;amp; height is 320px * 320px) Firstly we’re going to need to log in to &lt;a href=&quot;http://paypal.com&quot;&gt;Paypal&lt;/a&gt;. Once logged in direct yourself to the “Profile” drop-down and click on “My Selling Preferences”.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;From here under “Selling online” you’ll see the option “PayPal Buttons”. To the right you’ll either see “Get started” or “Update”. Click this link and you’ll be taken to the page where you can create a new “button”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you haven’t already created a PayPal button you’ll be taken straight to the button creation process, however if you already have an existing button you’ll be shown a list of all your currently active buttons. To being the creation process click the “Create new button” link to the right of the listed buttons already there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Now that we’re onto the button creation process be sure to choose “Donations” from the button type drop-down. Give your self an “Organization name / service” (i.e. your Twitch channel name or what-not) and then scroll down to the currency drop-down. Here you can select your native currency if you so wish to (USD, GBP etc).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;There are more options you can modify which I won’t go into on this post but may do in the future. Feel free to take your time and customize your donation button / process as much as you’d like to. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Once you’re done fiddling with the settings and what-not, click the “Save changes” button at the bottom and you’ll be taken to a page that gives you the website embed code and the direct email url. We want the e-mail one so click on the e-mail tab. Inside the text-box will be a link, this link is what we’ll link to an image on our Twitch channel so that people can click on the image and be taken to the PayPal checkout page so that they can donate to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;From here go to your Twitch channel (i.e. twitch.tv/yourname), scroll down and look for the “edit panels” toggle and the click “on” option. Now you can add a new panel or modify an existing panel if you so wish, simply click the “Add image” button, select your pre-made or pre-gathered donation button / image and then put the url you got from the e-mail tab in PayPal in the “Image links to” field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Give your panel a name such as “tip jar”, “donations” or whatever you want to call it, submit the panel and you’re done!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If this was hard for you to follow then feel free to check out the tutorial video I made on YouTube a while back that goes through this exact process, some might find it a lot easier to follow! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Please take note: PayPal’s “donation” button is designed for non-profit organizations. If you raise over $10,000 they will require proof you’re a non-profit organization. (Thank you to &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/joehills&quot;&gt;@joehills&lt;/a&gt; for pointing this out)&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitchtips.com/donation-panels-paypal/&quot;&gt;Donation panels (Paypal)&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Twitch Tips at &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitchtips.com&quot;&gt;Twitch Tips&lt;/a&gt; on April 14, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>


</feed>
